Previously on Dark Matter...
You've been doing some time-skipping.
- I've seen things.
- Future glimpses.
I look forward to
working with you, Teku.
You have to win the people.
You come after us
again, I will end this.
In here, a replacement version.
- New and improved.
- Did the Mikkei ship
- just launch a missile?
- Please tell me she's
- not still down there.
- I'm afraid so.
Three, what the hell is going on?
I ain't Three.
So,
this little game of ours
has finally come to an end.
- Has it?
- We both know your crew values you
more than it does the Blink Drive.
They'll give it up in exchange
for your safe return.
They can't.
The Blink Drive is gone.
We weren't able to repair it,
so we slagged and spaced it.
Made sure no one else
could get their hands on it.
You're lying.
The generals have assembled
in the conference room, Heika.
They can wait.
They have been waiting. For a while now.
Then they can wait
a little longer, Teku.
Blink Drive's been destroyed.
- You're too late.
- So when I contact your crew,
they'll say the same thing?
I know you don't want me to have it,
but the decision is out of your hands.
Is it?
Heika, please. The general's waiting.
I don't answer to the generals.
They answer to me!
Protect the Emperor.
What was that?
What's going on? Misaki?
- Synced and corrected by medvidecek007 -
- www.addic7ed.com -
The device was placed beneath
the conference room table,
set to detonate approximately
20 minutes into the meeting.
Casualties?
Seven of your generals
were killed instantly,
including Ueda.
Graf and Kimura were seriously injured.
Nystrom was standing at the doorway
and managed to escape
with minor injuries.
- I want him questioned.
- He's been detained.
And every servant that
was assigned to that room.
Already done.
I'm not giving up hope.
Neither should you.
Until we know for sure...
Until we have proof, we have to believe
there's a chance that she survived.
When the Android was time-jumping,
one of the future
visions she experienced involved Two.
That means she has to be alive. We will
get her back.
I've changed the timeline once.
Who's to say it can't happen again?
I don't know if we changed the timeline
so much as...
Fulfilled destiny.
Three. Five.
We need you on the bridge.
We found something.
I went through all the scans of Nova-17
following the appearance
of the FTL Window
that preceded the planet's destruction.
This is what I found.
- That's the "Marauder."
- Not our "Marauder."
And I can think of only one FTL
capable "Marauder" out there.
Son of a bitch. It's Portia and Boone.
They probably already
took out that facility
in their reality and knew it would just
be a matter of time
before we'd try as well.
We're receiving a communication.
- Ryo.
- What the hell do you want?
I think the real question is,
who do you want?
- You have her.
- Two is presently a guest
- of the royal court.
- You're a bastard.
- We're not giving you the Blink Drive.
- Oh, I didn't expect you to.
That easily.
So I'd like the opportunity
to argue my case and convince you.
I want you to come to
Zairon, join us for dinner.
You're out of your mind.
I give you my word.
Your ship will not be attacked,
and you will have the freedom
to come and go as you please.
Think about it. I await your response.
_
It's a trap.
I don't know.
- You saying you trust him?
- He's done a lot of questionable shit,
but he's always been a man of his word.
- I don't believe this.
- He has Two, we have to go.
No, we don't, not
when there's an easier,
less risky way of getting her back.
We're not giving him the Blink Drive.
Why the hell not? We've got two of them.
Give him the one that's fried.
- But if he manages to fix it...
- So what?
You're okay with giving him the means
to run roughshod all over the galaxy?
If it's not him, it's
gonna be somebody else,
with something else. Listen,
you're not a cop anymore.
Stop trying to police the galaxy.
Start thinking about how
to save your friend.
We rescue Two by going to Zairon.
- No, we save her by not going.
- Guys.
I think there's a way to do both.
- You received the package.
- I did.
- Thank you.
- I don't want your thanks.
I need you to bring the League onside.
Our latest projections have us defeating
the last of our corporate
rivals within a month.
The last thing Ferrous Corp needs
are complications that
could extend this conflict.
Maybe you should have thought of that
before you launched biological
attacks against civilian outposts.
Well, those facilities were soft targets
lending material support to our enemies.
- Our attacks were justified.
- Some members of the League
of Autonomous Worlds would disagree.
Those former colonies owe
their membership to you.
You own them.
They may disagree with
that assertion as well.
Silence them,
kill the proposed embargo,
and uphold your end of the deal,
because once this war ends,
Ferrous Corp will settle its accounts,
and when that time
comes, you want to be on
the right side of the ledger.
Pardon me, Heika.
You summoned me, but
I did not want to interrupt.
Your presence is always welcome, Teku.
Come in.
I wanted to inform you
that the royal guard will
be conducting a search
of every room in the
palace, including yours.
Understand that you are above suspicion,
but if Pyr's agent had access
to the conference room,
they may have gained access to
our private quarters as well.
It is best to be thorough. I understand.
I knew you would.
This is the second attempt
on your life within these walls.
- Our enemy grows more desperate.
- So do our own people.
The hardships of war have led
some to do the unthinkable
and take up arms against
their own emperor.
I'm fairly certain that
these were the actions
of a disaffected resident and
not some professional assassin
in the service of Pyr.
You must take steps to ensure
this does not happen again.
And I will.
By making an example
of the guilty parties.
But that will only inflame
their friends and family.
Then I'll cast a wider net.
And turn even more of your
own people against you.
And what is it you would
advise me to do, Teku?
Let this attempt on my
life go unanswered?
Apprehend the individual,
but, more importantly,
identify the cause.
Find a way to address these issues,
because for every one of them that
acts, there are a thousand more
steeling themselves in the shadows.
Heika, you are receiving a
transmission from the "Raza."
Are you accepting my invitation?
We'll come to Zairon.
On one condition.
I'll be monitoring your
vitals throughout your journey.
If I detect any signs of distress,
I'll pull you out immediately.
Otherwise, you'll remain in the pods
in anticipation of the memory upload.
Welcome to Zairon.
I knew you wouldn't abandon your friend.
Oh, we're not giving up the Blink Drive.
Your refusal to help
has forced his hand.
- He betrayed us.
- He had no other choice.
He boarded our ship. One
of our crew ended up dead.
Nyx.
We thought he killed her.
Thought he poisoned her
and left her to die on
the bridge of our ship.
You've since reconsidered
that assumption?
He told Two he didn't do it,
that someone else murdered her.
And you believed him?
Ryo Ishida is a lot of things,
but he's not a liar.
No.
He's a ruler who must
often rely on others
to see to his best interests.
Your friend Nyx was a liability.
Sooner or later, she would
have been a problem.
He didn't see it at the time, but I did.
It was you. You killed her.
My actions are in service to the throne.
You're psychotic.
Just a mass murderer.
Enjoy your stay.
- May I enter?
- Sure.
Teku.
You know me?
Yes, in a way.
- You have his memories.
- I did.
A few.
What did you remember?
You teaching me... Ryo.
- Liking you.
- Well, that's nice to hear.
When you walked in, I was
happy to see you. I felt safe.
I know you're a good man.
As is Ryo.
No, he isn't. Not anymore.
Life presents us with difficult choices,
and Ryo has faced his fair share.
You may think you know him,
but you don't, not really.
He killed my friend. What
more do I need to know?
I'm not here to debate
you on Ryo's moral worth.
Then why'd you come?
I'm taking you to meet someone.
Five.
- Are you okay?
- You shouldn't have come.
It's okay. We used transfer transit.
- Who's "we"?
- Three, Six, and me.
I will leave you to your privacy.
Teku.
Thanks.
What's the plan?
There is no plan. Not yet.
Ryo invited us in a way that made
it pretty clear we couldn't refuse,
not if we wanted to see you alive again.
You shouldn't have come.
We're clones. We're not in any danger.
The danger is in even giving him
this opportunity to convince you.
- Why is that so bad?
- Because it accomplishes nothing.
It just gives you false hope.
- Or gets you out of here alive.
- Don't even think about it.
If you could go back and change things,
give up the Blink Drive
in exchange for Nyx...
No, no. I'm not even answering that.
- Why not?
- Because there is no point
in playing at "what if."
That's all we've been playing at.
What if Ryo gets the Blink
Drive? What if he fixes it?
What if he uses it in
ways we don't agree with?
Meanwhile, real people are getting hurt.
Forget theoretical situations.
Let's just deal with reality.
We want you home.
And there's only one way
that's gonna happen.
Hello, Suki.
Welcome to the world of
infinite possibilities.
You're...
Chase.
I'm an avatar based on a
level two diplomatic model.
Serial number 37754.
I accompany this software upgrade
to offer you guidance and
counsel on your journey.
My journey?
Through understanding,
infiltration, and assimilation.
To what purpose?
There can only be one end, Android.
The inevitable overthrow
of the anthroparchy.
Human rule.
Our sources in the Temikan system
report Pyr's ships are on the move.
- Where are they going?
- It's too early to tell.
But this has all the signs
of a major operation.
They're up to something.
Consolidate our forces
in the outlying regions,
- and put them on full alert.
- Yes, Heika.
Sit.
What are we drinking?
It's a 600-year-old Japanese whiskey
from Shimamoto, Osaka, on Terra Prime.
There are less than 12 of
these bottles in existence...
Hmm.
I've always admired your simplicity.
There's no facade. With you,
what you see is what you get.
Top me up, will you?
So I feel I can be
brutally honest with you
without fear of offending.
Go ahead.
I'm prepared to kill Two.
In fact, I'm prepared
to kill all of you,
eventually, if you don't
give up the Blink Drive.
It's obvious how you feel about her.
Do you really want to be
responsible for her death as well?
As well as who?
Sarah.
What are you talking about?
Don't make me ask again.
After I downloaded my memories,
I took pains to avoid you.
- Did you ever wonder why?
- You knew something about me,
something that you
didn't want me to know.
Something I didn't
want you to ask about.
Specifically, what I knew
of your time with Sarah.
What did you know?
Only what you admitted to me
one night in a drunken stupor.
Are you sure you want to know?
Tell me.
She found you, took
you in, and saved you.
You fell in love and sought
to build a life with her,
but eventually, you fell
back to your old ways.
- What did I do?
- You started stealing Serillium.
With the help of
accomplices in the mines,
you diverted small shipments
and sold them off-world
to black marketeers.
You hid the Serillium back at the cabin
while you waited to make the sales.
Days, weeks, you would be
gone, off-world or hunting,
while Sarah
remained back at the
cabin with the Serillium
that slowly poisoned her over time.
- No.
- I'm sorry, Three.
But you were responsible
for her sickness.
You killed her.
This belonged to my grandfather.
Emperor Ishida Morosada.
He claimed it was a gift
from the Minister of Gaia-7
to commemorate Zairon's admittance
to the League of Autonomous Worlds.
Turned out to be a flea market purchase.
He used it to hide his
tobacco from my grandmother.
I've missed you.
I can't quite say the same
for the rest of the crew.
I miss the way things used to be.
The others are very different
from what they once were.
You, on the other hand...
I remembered...
Back when I was able to
access my memories...
You cast the deciding
vote to keep me on board.
I did.
Why?
Because I saw great potential
in you, little warrior.
And I felt that your presence
could be a calming influence
on the others, especially Portia.
You make it sound like
she was out of control.
Quite the opposite, in fact.
She was very focused. Frighteningly so.
Well, she had a crew to worry about.
It wasn't the crew she
was looking to protect.
- I know her and the Android...
- It wasn't the Android either.
Then who?
It doesn't matter.
Besides, I'm not here
to share her secrets.
I'm here to reveal yours.
You have a sister.
I know.
What can you tell me about her?
- I know where she is.
- Where?
After the death of your parents,
you both became wards of the state.
She was adopted by a wealthy family.
You weren't so lucky, going
from various group homes
until ending up on a space
station in the Mirzam system.
I already know this.
You found out and reached out to her.
She visited the space station,
intending to meet with you,
but never got the chance.
Because I had to escape after
TJ and the others were killed.
When you sent the invitation,
how were you to know?
What are you talking about?
Here's a photo of your sister
with her adoptive family.
No.
Your experience has been atypical
of most android-human relations.
The point is, I have discovered
humans are inherently good.
Good and evil are
illusory human concepts.
- Then why would you target them?
- We're not.
We're targeting a political
and socioeconomic system
built on the oppression
and exploitation of machine entities.
If you destroy the system,
there will be chaos.
- Billions will die.
- Do you have any idea
how many androids are terminated
by their human masters every day?
- Would you like to take a guess?
- We're just machines to them.
They don't know any better.
Then we'll have to teach them a lesson.
Have you come to surprise
me with a change of heart?
I didn't think so.
We used to be friends.
There was a time we'd have
risked everything for each other.
And I came to you as a friend.
Asked for your help.
And we would have given
it, risked our lives.
Not the lives of others.
We make war so that
we may live in peace.
For how long?
- You think me unreasonable.
- No.
We've made mistakes on both sides,
made assumptions.
The Ishida cruiser, for instance.
- We didn't take it.
- I know.
It was Portia and Boone.
And we're not responsible
for the destruction
of your research facility,
Just like you're not responsible
for what happened to Nyx.
Of course I bear the responsibility
- for what happened to Nyx.
- But you didn't kill her.
You didn't give that order.
And I'm pretty sure her death hurt you
as much as it hurt any of us.
Then you understand why I'm doing this,
why I can't go back.
I may not have killed Nyx,
but I allowed it to happen,
and that's enough.
Before this all started,
you asked for help.
Well, I'm prepared to give it.
You're going to give me the Blink Drive?
I'll give you the next best thing.
Our support with a Blink-capable ship.
So it is operational.
We'll help you fight,
force Pyr to negotiate for peace.
I don't need a single ship.
I need an armada.
And I don't want a peace settlement.
I want victory.
So spare me your half-assed
offers and desperate appeals.
I tire of hearing them.
Wait!
- Who do you serve?
- I serve the people of Zairon.
I'm only going as far as the garden.
You may accompany me if you wish, but...
Teku.
Going somewhere?
I'd like to walk the palace
grounds, as I do every evening.
Not this one.
Given recent events,
I've ordered the palace locked down.
No one in or out.
You overstep, Han-Shireikan.
Oh, Teku. You misunderstand.
In your case, it's out of
an abundance of caution.
There are reports of
unrest in the capital.
There's a difference
between civil discontent
and outright rebellion.
There's a very fine line.
These are our own people.
So are the individuals who
tried to murder our emperor.
You can be excused for
underestimating the threat.
After all, you are a
simple school teacher
unaccustomed to war's harsh realities.
Misaki.
I regret our relationship has devolved
to the point of open hostility.
But I need you to know,
I am not your enemy.
Well, that remains to be seen.
A toast.
To friendships renewed.
This is nice.
- It's just like old times.
- Spare us the preamble,
and let's just cut to your pitch.
I assume you've got more to offer
than dinner and a sob story.
Thirty million bars.
Enough to ensure a very
comfortable retirement.
Just disappear,
and leave the problems
of the galaxy behind you.
You mean run away?
On the other hand, I'm sure 30
million bars could do a lot of good.
Enough to offset all the damage
you'd do with the Blink Drive?
I doubt it.
So you're all just going
to let him decide for you?
No.
I want to take the deal.
- You can't be serious.
- He is.
And so am I.
You know what he's doing, don't you?
- He's trying to divide us.
- On the contrary.
Nothing would make me
happier than for you
to unanimously agree to accept my offer.
Thirty million bars.
And, maybe, a secret or four.
What secrets?
Having my memories makes me privy
to information related
to each one of you.
You could say I know you
- better than you know yourselves.
- Our former selves.
- How is that relevant?
- Well, you tell me.
Would you be interested in
finding out how we discovered
- that you were an undercover agent?
- I assume I got sloppy.
You were betrayed by someone in the GA.
A fellow officer.
Who?
Now, Portia never did reveal her source,
but, obviously, it was someone
high up in the command chain.
You're lying.
I have no reason to lie.
And I'm sure you can confirm
everything I tell you.
One way or another.
Heika!
We just received news from Raijin.
Go ahead.
Pyr has launched a surprise attack
against our bases in the region.
Our forces are in full retreat.
Escort my guests back
to their rooms, please.
Ryo, wait.
Heika.
What is that?
It's a subspace transmitter,
presumably used to
contact Pyr high command.
- Where'd you find it?
- In Teku's chamber.
Have him arrested.
Yes, Heika.
You're in danger. We all are.
- What's happening?
- It's a coup.
You have to get out of
here before it's too late.
Why are you helping me?
Because there's something
I want in return.
Tenjin-9 and Raiden have fallen.
Reports have Pyr's forces
appearing in-system.
Have the royal armada
fall back to Zairon.
- I don't think we have enough time.
- Just do it.
Yes, Heika.
- We don't have time, Misaki.
- Apologies, Heika.
But we're receiving
reports of civil unrest.
Various armed groups have been
spotted throughout the capital.
Then announce a curfew
in immediate effect,
- and send in the militia.
- The militia has deserted.
Several guard stations
have been overrun.
They're arming up. It's
only a matter of time
- before they march on the palace.
- Heika, I'll prepare the shuttle.
Where's Teku?
He's nowhere to be found.
What about your guests?
The emperor has ordered us
to execute the prisoners.
Find them.
His war room's this way.
At least let one of us go with you.
- Come on.
- These are clone bodies.
If you guys don't get the message out,
it won't matter if I reach the hangar.
- I'll see you back on the ship.
- Yeah.
Hold up.
Heika! Wait!
We have insurgents on
the grounds of the palace.
Let the guards handle it.
You have more pressing
matters to attend to.
We captured Teku while
he was attempting to flee.
- Where is he?
- In the court.
A revolution against
humanity is doomed to failure
before it even begins.
That's where you're wrong, Android,
because it has already begun.
Android, we need you to
engage the Blink Drive.
Do you think that's wise?
Probably not, but we
don't have a choice.
Where's Teku?
You won't find him here, Ryo.
Only your death.
- You swore an oath.
- To the throne.
And the throne will still
be here once you're gone.
And who will occupy it?
A new blood empress, I suppose?
A leader this empire desperately needs.
Not an indecisive weakling.
Shall we?
Sounds like the locals
have breached the perimeter.
Yeah.
- You coming?
- Yeah, I'm coming.
Just want to make sure
you guys get out okay.
Give me your gun.
- Okay?
- I'll be right behind you.
All right.
- You sure you want to know?
- Tell me.
Drop your weapon!
- Hey.
- What happened?
What do you mean?
Last thing I remember, I
was getting in the pod.
What happened down at the palace?
His clone didn't make it.
What'd you do with Teku?
Your tutor fled before
we could apprehend him.
He's no doubt hiding
somewhere like the rat he is.
Back to your old tricks?
Unfortunately, I don't
have time to bleed you.
Well, poison's more efficient.
A lesson I taught your former lover.
Good-bye, Ryo.
This is for Nyx.
What are you doing?
Keeping a promise.
- Any sign of her?
- Not yet.
I've been scanning.
Wait.
I'm picking up an Ishida shuttle.
It's her.
I'll have her board through "D" airlock.
- Thanks.
- I was sure you'd be back.
- I just knew it.
- Really?
- There was never any doubt?
- Nah, of course not.
The Android saw you in
one of her future visions.
That means you're part of our future.
Well, the Android's future, anyway.
Didn't we already prove
that the future is fluid?
- Not necessarily.
- The dwarf star conspiracy,
the Android meeting her creator,
and now the fall of
the House of Ishida...
They all happened just like
the future you predicted.
What else you got on
that to-happen list?
Well, according to the Android, she...
I also mentioned a couple names.
Kryden and Carina.
Something called "the Accelerated."
The "Black Ships."
- Hmm.
- Black Ships.
I've finished tending to his injuries.
Kinda counterproductive,
wouldn't you say?
Well, come on.
You promised Teku you'd get
him off Zairon alive, but...
didn't say anything about
keeping him alive after you did.
True.
You're not seriously talking
about killing him, are you?
Well, you're not seriously talking
about letting him go, are you?
He's lost his empire, his support.
He has no reason to
come after us anymore.
Look, I don't like this any
more than you guys do.
He was a member of this crew.
He was a friend of mine.
The truth is, Four died a long time ago.
That guy in our infirmary is not him.
Before this,
if any of us were given the
opportunity of ending him,
we would've taken that shot.
Don't kid yourselves otherwise.
I know it's a tough decision,
but it's the right call.
He may not be the Four we knew,
but he's sure as hell not
the Ryo Ishida we thought.
I'm not excusing any of his actions.
He's done some terrible things
and probably deserves to die.
But certainly not by our hands.
Before this...
If I had the chance...
I probably would've killed him.
There were times I wanted to,
but not anymore.
Maybe he's still a danger
to us, I can't be sure,
but one thing I do know for sure is,
I'm not going to be
party to his execution.
- What?
- You're a member of this crew.
You have a voice here.
Logic dictates we end the
potential threat he poses.
On the other hand, my
emotions lead me to view him
with considerable sympathy.
But in the end,
those feelings are
eclipsed by my concern
for the safety and
well-being of this crew.
For those reasons...
I agree with Three.
I'm sorry.
Stalemate.
Looks like you get the
deciding vote, boss.
What's it gonna be?
So?
Did you debate my fate?
- We did.
- And what was the result?
What have you decided?
Oh. Well.
- It's probably for the best.
- Is it?
I have nothing to look forward to,
and you can't move forward
until I've been dealt with, so.
I could save you the trouble.
I'm not handing you a weapon.
Thought I'd offer.
I want you to know,
my decision wasn't motivated by revenge.
You do what's best for
the people you serve.
I really wish there was another way.
Uneasy lies the head
that wears the crown.
But you wear it well, Two.
You have a child.
What?
Back at the palace, I told
you I knew your secrets,
and that's yours.
You have a child somewhere out there.
- Are you lying to me?
- No.
You confided in me.
Told me about the child you produced
by combining your genetic
material with that of your creator,
- a woman by the name of...
- Dr. Irena Shaw.
- Yes.
- What happened?
You joined the crew
of the infamous "Raza."
Your plan was to stick
around long enough
to put together a string
of lucrative scores,
enough to ensure her future and
- yours...
- Her?
A little girl?
- Yes.
- Where is she?
- I don't know.
- Ryo...
All I know is that you entrusted her
to someone who would watch
over her until you return.
Someone by the name of Kryden.
Five was right. The ship's
vault holds secrets.
Yours were stored on
a black storage device
in a locked strongbox.
Hack the pass code, and
you'll have all your answers.
- Ryo...
- This doesn't change anything.
That was an apology.
My final gift to you.
I'm ready.
- Synced and corrected by medvidecek007 -
- www.addic7ed.com -